<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MusicTutorApp</string>
    <string name="welcome_message">Welcome back</string>
    <string name="practical_support">Practical Support</string>
    <string name="plectrum_lesson"><b>Lesson 4 - </b>A plectrum is a small flat tool used to pluck or strum a guitar. A pick (aka plectrum) is used to get the brightest and best sound from a guitar, especially in Pop and Rock music. \n\n
        Some beginners are very reluctant to use a pick. However, ESPECIALLY in the early days, I really recommend persisting no matter how many times it
        spins around in your hand or how often you drop it. It is simply the easiest way to get the best sound from your guitar for most pop and rock styles.
        Once you have a solid foundation of chords and rhythm, you can always learn folk ‘finger style’ playing at a later date.</string>
    <string name="chord_lesson"><b>Lesson 5 - </b>Chord boxes show us where to put our fingers for each chord. Here is the chord box for the E Chord (E major). The black dots show where to place your fingers. And the numbers show which finger you should use (1 is index finger, 2 is middle finger etc). In this chord above, we strum all 6 strings on the guitar.</string>
    <string name="question_example"><b>Question 10 - </b> What is a plectrum used for with the guitar?</string>

    <string name="level1_intro_welcome_title">Level 1: Introduction</string>
    <string name="level1_intro_welcome">Welcome to the first level of GuitarPal! The lessons, tips and tools in this app will introduce you to the basics of the guitar and start you on your way to becoming an accomplished guitar player. \nThere is a knowledge test at the end of each level that you must pass in order to unlock the next level. \n\nYou must get at least 80% on each test to pass! Sounds tricky? FEAR NOT! Read through the lessons and you will pass with flying colours!\nYou can easily swipe through each lesson from left to right and scroll up and down throughout each lesson in every level!</string>

    <string name="level1_intro">In level 1, you will be introduced to the various parts of the guitar, how to hold a guitar and hold a plectrum. So swipe the screen to the left and lets begin!</string>
    <string name="swipe_left">Swipe left to begin!</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson1_title">Lesson 1: Parts of an Acoustic Guitar</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson1_tv1">Welcome to Lesson 1 of GuitarPal! Once you\'ve purchased your guitar, it\'s time to learn all the parts that comprise the acoustic guitar. This information will come in handy when it comes time for repairs or general maintenance, which are always essential to being a guitar player.</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson1_tv2"><b>Body:</b> The body of the acoustic guitar is what gives the instrument its sound and beauty. Its the big hollow shape, or sound box, that resonates when you play the strings. Its what makes the guitar sound like a guitar.
                                        \n\n<b>Neck:</b> The guitar neck is the long wooden shaft that tapers down to the headstock. Each string runs along this extension, and depending on where your fingers are placed on each string up and down the neck, you make different tones that resonate throughout the guitar. The face of the neck is called the fretboard because that is where the guitar frets are located.
                                        \n\n<b>Head (Headstock):</b> At the end of the guitar neck, there is the headstock. It is fitted with tuners or machine heads that adjust the tension of the strings, therefore changing the pitch of the guitar.
                                        \n\n<b>Tuners (Machine Heads):</b> These metal pegs adjust the tension of the guitar strings to raise or lower their pitches depending on whether or not you turn them clockwise or counterclockwise.
                                        \n\n<b>Nut: </b>The nut is the thin white piece that separates the neck from the headstock. It separates each guitar string going down the neck so that they are evenly spaced out in order to be played.
                                        \n\n<b>Frets:</b> Frets are the thin metal pieces on the fretboard that run perpendicular to the guitar neck, and act as tone separators for the guitar. They separate the guitar neck into semitones or half steps making the guitar neck act as a grid from which you play musical tones.
                                        \n\n<b>Sound Hole: </b>The sound hole is the reason that sound escapes the body of the guitar. When a string is plucked, this sound bounces around the inside of the guitar, eventually escaping through the sound hole and into our ears.
                                        \n\n<b>Bridge:</b> The bridge of the guitar holds the guitar strings firmly on the body so that they do not loose tension and therefore change pitch. When a string is plucked, vibrations run from the bridge all the way down the neck to the nut.
                                        \n\n<b>Bridge Pegs:</b> These are used on acoustic guitars to fasten the ends of the strings to the bridge. They are the nails that keep each string secured to the wooden bridge.
                                        \n\n<b>Pickguard: </b>Over time, strumming with a pick can do some wear and tear. Thats why the pickguard is there to protect the guitars body from dings and scratches.</string>

    <string name="level1_lesson2_title">Lesson 2: Parts of an Electric Guitar</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson2_tv1">There is no real difference between the electric guitar and the acoustic guitar when it comes to playing, if you can play one, you can play the other! You can see below that the electric also has a body, a neck, a freboard and headstock.</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson2_tv2"><b>Pickguard:</b> Over time, strumming with a pick can do some wear and tear. That\'s why the pickguard is there to protect the guitars body from dings and scratches.
                                        \n\n<b>Strap Button: </b>There are two strap buttons on an electric guitar: one at the top of the body and one at the base. These are there to hold your guitar strap in place when you\’re using one to stand and play guitar at the same time.</string>
     <string name="level1_lesson2_tv3"><b>Bridge:</b> The bridge of the guitar holds the guitar strings firmly on the body so that they do not loose tension and therefore change pitch. When a string is plucked, vibrations run from the bridge all the way down the neck to the nut. Each string on the electric guitar is assigned to its own metal spring piece on the bridge called a saddle. These saddles can be adjusted to slightly alter the tension of each string therefore changing the string\'s intonation.
                                        \n\n<b>Pickups:</b> While acoustics use sound holes to release sound, electrics use pickups. Pickups are small microphones, or transducers that pick up the vibrations from each string and convert them into electrical signals.
                                        \n\n<b>Pickup Selector (Toggle Switch):</b> This switch triggers which pickups are going to be used to make the sound of the strings. The number of pickups can vary depending on which guitar you have, so you may have anywhere from a 5 setting toggle switch or no switch at all.
                                        \n\n<b>Volume Knob:</b> This knob adjusts the amount of power you are giving the pickups, ultimately adjusting how loud or quite your guitar is.
                                        \n\n<b>Tone Knobs: </b>These knobs adjust precisely how the pickups sound (treble and bass). Depending on which way you turn them, your guitar may sound bright and tinny, or dark and muffled.
                                        \n\n<b>Output Jack:</b> The output jack is where you insert the power cable that connects to your amplifier. This jack is how the electronic signals from the pickups travel out of the guitar, through an amplifier and into our ears.</string>


    <string name="level1_lesson3_title">Lesson 3: How to Hold the Guitar</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson3_tv1">Learning the correct way to hold your guitar can mean the difference between making something easier to play and making something harder to play on guitar. Once you learn how to properly position your guitar, learning to play will feel intuitive and natural.</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson3_tv2"><b>Step 1: </b>Find a comfortable chair without arms. This will give you more freedom to move around while you\'re playing the guitar.
                                    \n\n<b>Step 2: </b>Place the guitar on the top of your right knee. If you were left handed, you would place the guitar on the top of your left knee.
                                    \n\n<b>Step 3: </b>Tilt the guitar back towards you slightly. This limits the amount of stretching your left hand has to do while playing and therefore making the instrument easier to play than if it were tilted away from you.
                                    \n\n<b>Step 4: </b>Your strumming hand should rest comfortably on the guitar in such a way that your wrist is poised right above the pickups (or sound hole on acoustics).
                                    \n\n<b>Step 5: </b>The neck should be parallel to the floor. You will get the most comfort and playing versatility out of holding the guitar this way.
                                    \n\n<b>Step 6: </b>Make sure that the thickest string is the string that\'s closest to you. This holds true for both right and left handed guitars.
                                    \n\n<b>Step 7: </b>With your left hand (or right hand if you\'re left handed), place your thumb on the back of the guitar neck, right in the middle. This way, your fingers will curl around the neck easily and comfortably to put you in the correct playing position.</string>

    <string name="level1_lesson4_title">Lesson 4: How to Hold a Guitar Pick</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson4_tv1"><b>1.</b>	Hold your picking hand (the one that holds the pick) so that the back of the thumb is facing upwards.
                                        \n\n<b>2.</b> Relax the hand completely, this should allow the fingers to curl up.
                                        \n\n<b>3.</b> Place the pick on to the side of your index finger. The pointed end of the pick should face toward the nail of your index finger.
                                        \n\n<b>4.</b> Place your thumb onto the pick to keep it clamped between your thumb and finger.
</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson4_tv2">Make sure your grip on the pick is relaxed. Do not squeeze the pick. Have the pick positioned at a 10% angle to the string, not completely parallel. How you hold the pick is a matter of personal taste, however, there are guidelines on how to hold a pick. Fast lead playing requires small, consistent motions so only 2mm of the tip of the pick should be used (as a rough guideline), whereas strumming requires a more open grip on the pick.
                                        \n\nShould I Use a Pick?
                                        \n\nNot every one will chose to use a pick, especially folk guitarists and similar style players. Non pick users will use either finger picking or hybrid picking (both pick and fingers). Using fingerpicks and thumbpicks should be referred to as finger picking because using them employs the same movements and style.
                                        \n\nPicks come in all shapes and sizes, ranging from 0.36mm to 3mm in thickness and from the size of a thumbnail to a 50p piece. Strumming chords favours a thin pick but thickness is a clear advantage for single-note pieces. Beginners tend to favour thinner picks but usually use thicker picks as they get used to the feel of them. A 0.9mm pick is a good all-rounder.
</string>


</resources>
