<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MusicTutorApp</string>
    <string name="welcome_message">Welcome back</string>
    <string name="practical_support">Practical Support</string>
    <string name="plectrum_lesson"><b>Lesson 4 - </b>A plectrum is a small flat tool used to pluck or strum a guitar. A pick (aka plectrum) is used to get the brightest and best sound from a guitar, especially in Pop and Rock music. \n\n
        Some beginners are very reluctant to use a pick. However, ESPECIALLY in the early days, I really recommend persisting no matter how many times it
        spins around in your hand or how often you drop it. It is simply the easiest way to get the best sound from your guitar for most pop and rock styles.
        Once you have a solid foundation of chords and rhythm, you can always learn folk ‘finger style’ playing at a later date.</string>
    <string name="chord_lesson"><b>Lesson 5 - </b>Chord boxes show us where to put our fingers for each chord. Here is the chord box for the E Chord (E major). The black dots show where to place your fingers. And the numbers show which finger you should use (1 is index finger, 2 is middle finger etc). In this chord above, we strum all 6 strings on the guitar.</string>
    <string name="question_example"><b>Question 10 - </b> What is a plectrum used for with the guitar?</string>

    <string name="level1_intro_welcome_title">Level 1: Introduction</string>
    <string name="level1_intro_welcome">Welcome to the first level of GuitarPal! The lessons, tips and tools in this app will introduce you to the basics of the guitar and start you on your way to becoming an accomplished guitar player. \nThere is a knowledge test at the end of each level that you must pass in order to unlock the next level. \n\nYou must get at least 80% on each test to pass! Sounds tricky? FEAR NOT! Read through the lessons and you will pass with flying colours!\nYou can easily swipe through each lesson from left to right and scroll up and down throughout each lesson in every level!</string>

    <string name="level1_intro">In level 1, we will be introduced to the various parts of the guitar, how to hold a guitar and hold a plectrum. So swipe the screen to the left and lets begin! Or alternatively you can take the level 1 test now!</string>
    <string name="swipe_left">Swipe left to begin! Or alternatively you can take the level 1 test now!</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson1_title">Lesson 1: Parts of an Acoustic Guitar</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson1_tv1">Welcome to Lesson 1 of GuitarPal! Once you\'ve purchased your guitar, it\'s time to learn all the parts that comprise the acoustic guitar. This information will come in handy when it comes time for repairs or general maintenance, which are always essential to being a guitar player.</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson1_tv2"><b>Body:</b> The body of the acoustic guitar is what gives the instrument its sound and beauty. Its the big hollow shape, or sound box, that resonates when you play the strings. Its what makes the guitar sound like a guitar.
                                        \n\n<b>Neck:</b> The guitar neck is the long wooden shaft that tapers down to the headstock. Each string runs along this extension, and depending on where your fingers are placed on each string up and down the neck, you make different tones that resonate throughout the guitar. The face of the neck is called the fretboard because that is where the guitar frets are located.
                                        \n\n<b>Head (Headstock):</b> At the end of the guitar neck, there is the headstock. It is fitted with tuners or machine heads that adjust the tension of the strings, therefore changing the pitch of the guitar.
                                        \n\n<b>Tuners (Machine Heads):</b> These metal pegs adjust the tension of the guitar strings to raise or lower their pitches depending on whether or not you turn them clockwise or counterclockwise.
                                        \n\n<b>Nut: </b>The nut is the thin white piece that separates the neck from the headstock. It separates each guitar string going down the neck so that they are evenly spaced out in order to be played.
                                        \n\n<b>Frets:</b> Frets are the thin metal pieces on the fretboard that run perpendicular to the guitar neck, and act as tone separators for the guitar. They separate the guitar neck into semitones or half steps making the guitar neck act as a grid from which you play musical tones.
                                        \n\n<b>Sound Hole: </b>The sound hole is the reason that sound escapes the body of the guitar. When a string is plucked, this sound bounces around the inside of the guitar, eventually escaping through the sound hole and into our ears.
                                        \n\n<b>Bridge:</b> The bridge of the guitar holds the guitar strings firmly on the body so that they do not loose tension and therefore change pitch. When a string is plucked, vibrations run from the bridge all the way down the neck to the nut.
                                        \n\n<b>Bridge Pegs:</b> These are used on acoustic guitars to fasten the ends of the strings to the bridge. They are the nails that keep each string secured to the wooden bridge.
                                        \n\n<b>Pickguard: </b>Over time, strumming with a pick can do some wear and tear. Thats why the pickguard is there to protect the guitars body from dings and scratches.</string>

    <string name="level1_lesson2_title">Lesson 2: Parts of an Electric Guitar</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson2_tv1">There is no real difference between the electric guitar and the acoustic guitar when it comes to playing, if you can play one, you can play the other! You can see below that the electric also has a body, a neck, a freboard and headstock.</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson2_tv2"><b>Pickguard:</b> Over time, strumming with a pick can do some wear and tear. That\'s why the pickguard is there to protect the guitars body from dings and scratches.
                                        \n\n<b>Strap Button: </b>There are two strap buttons on an electric guitar: one at the top of the body and one at the base. These are there to hold your guitar strap in place when you\’re using one to stand and play guitar at the same time.</string>
     <string name="level1_lesson2_tv3"><b>Bridge:</b> The bridge of the guitar holds the guitar strings firmly on the body so that they do not loose tension and therefore change pitch. When a string is plucked, vibrations run from the bridge all the way down the neck to the nut. Each string on the electric guitar is assigned to its own metal spring piece on the bridge called a saddle. These saddles can be adjusted to slightly alter the tension of each string therefore changing the string\'s intonation.
                                        \n\n<b>Pickups:</b> While acoustics use sound holes to release sound, electrics use pickups. Pickups are small microphones, or transducers that pick up the vibrations from each string and convert them into electrical signals.
                                        \n\n<b>Pickup Selector (Toggle Switch):</b> This switch triggers which pickups are going to be used to make the sound of the strings. The number of pickups can vary depending on which guitar you have, so you may have anywhere from a 5 setting toggle switch or no switch at all.
                                        \n\n<b>Volume Knob:</b> This knob adjusts the amount of power you are giving the pickups, ultimately adjusting how loud or quite your guitar is.
                                        \n\n<b>Tone Knobs: </b>These knobs adjust precisely how the pickups sound (treble and bass). Depending on which way you turn them, your guitar may sound bright and tinny, or dark and muffled.
                                        \n\n<b>Output Jack:</b> The output jack is where you insert the power cable that connects to your amplifier. This jack is how the electronic signals from the pickups travel out of the guitar, through an amplifier and into our ears.</string>

    <string name="level1_lesson3_title">Lesson 3: How to Hold the Guitar</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson3_tv1">Learning the correct way to hold your guitar can mean the difference between making something easier to play and making something harder to play on guitar. Once you learn how to properly position your guitar, learning to play will feel intuitive and natural.</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson3_tv2"><b>Step 1: </b>Find a comfortable chair without arms. This will give you more freedom to move around while you\'re playing the guitar.
                                    \n\n<b>Step 2: </b>Place the guitar on the top of your right knee. If you were left handed, you would place the guitar on the top of your left knee.
                                    \n\n<b>Step 3: </b>Tilt the guitar back towards you slightly. This limits the amount of stretching your left hand has to do while playing and therefore making the instrument easier to play than if it were tilted away from you.
                                    \n\n<b>Step 4: </b>Your strumming hand should rest comfortably on the guitar in such a way that your wrist is poised right above the pickups (or sound hole on acoustics).
                                    \n\n<b>Step 5: </b>The neck should be parallel to the floor. You will get the most comfort and playing versatility out of holding the guitar this way.
                                    \n\n<b>Step 6: </b>Make sure that the thickest string is the string that\'s closest to you. This holds true for both right and left handed guitars.
                                    \n\n<b>Step 7: </b>With your left hand (or right hand if you\'re left handed), place your thumb on the back of the guitar neck, right in the middle. This way, your fingers will curl around the neck easily and comfortably to put you in the correct playing position.</string>

    <string name="level1_lesson4_title">Lesson 4: How to Hold a Guitar Pick</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson4_tv1"><b>1.</b>	Hold your picking hand (the one that holds the pick) so that the back of the thumb is facing upwards.
                                        \n\n<b>2.</b> Relax the hand completely, this should allow the fingers to curl up.
                                        \n\n<b>3.</b> Place the pick on to the side of your index finger. The pointed end of the pick should face toward the nail of your index finger.
                                        \n\n<b>4.</b> Place your thumb onto the pick to keep it clamped between your thumb and finger.</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson4_tv2">Make sure your grip on the pick is relaxed. Do not squeeze the pick. Have the pick positioned at a 10% angle to the string, not completely parallel. How you hold the pick is a matter of personal taste, however, there are guidelines on how to hold a pick. Fast lead playing requires small, consistent motions so only 2mm of the tip of the pick should be used (as a rough guideline), whereas strumming requires a more open grip on the pick.
                                        \n\nShould I Use a Pick?
                                        \n\nNot every one will chose to use a pick, especially folk guitarists and similar style players. Non pick users will use either finger picking or hybrid picking (both pick and fingers). Using fingerpicks and thumbpicks should be referred to as finger picking because using them employs the same movements and style.
                                        \n\nPicks come in all shapes and sizes, ranging from 0.36mm to 3mm in thickness and from the size of a thumbnail to a 50p piece. Strumming chords favours a thin pick but thickness is a clear advantage for single-note pieces. Beginners tend to favour thinner picks but usually use thicker picks as they get used to the feel of them. A 0.9mm pick is a good all-rounder.</string>

    <string name="level1_lesson5_title">Lesson 5: Names of the Guitar Strings</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson5_tv1">In order to be a guitarist, it\'s absolutely crucial that you memorize the 6 strings on a guitar. Well then, what are they?</string>
    <string name="level1_lesson5_tv2">The thickest string is called the 6th string. In standard guitar tuning, this is tuned to E. We often refer to this as the \‘low E string\‘. This is the deepest/lowest guitar note you can play.
                                        \n\nThe 5th string is tuned to A, so it\’s usually referred to as the A string.
                                        \n\nThe 4th string is tuned to D, so it\’s usually referred to as the D string.
                                        \n\nThe 3rd string is tuned to G, so it\’s usually referred to as the G string.
                                        \n\nThe 2nd string is tuned to B, so it\’s usually referred to as the B string.
                                        \n\nThe 1st string is tuned to E. This is the thinnest of all the strings. We often refer to this as the \‘high E string\’.</string>
     <string name="level1_lesson5_tv3">\n\nHow to remember the guitar string names? The easiest way to remember the guitar string names is to use a mnemonic. The sillier the better! Here\’s a couple of fun ways to remember this:
                                        \n\n(Going from the thickest string to the thinnest…)
                                        \n\n<b>Elephants</b>
                                        \n\n<b>And</b>
                                        \n\n<b>Donkeys</b>
                                        \n\n<b>Grow</b>
                                        \n\n<b>Big</b>
                                        \n\n<b>Ears</b></string>

    <string name="level2_intro_title">Level 2: Introduction</string>
    <string name="level2_intro_tv1">Welcome to the second level of GuitarPal!</string>
    <string name="level2_intro_tv2">\nIn this level, we will be introduced to various extremely important aspects of playing guitar such as how to tune a guitar, getting to know the fretboard and how to read chord charts and guitar tabs. So swipe the screen to the left and lets begin!\n\n Or alternatively you can take the level 2 test now!</string>

    <string name="level2_lesson1_title">Lesson 1: How to Tune a Guitar</string>
    <string name="level2_lesson1_tv1">It is essential for any guitarist to keep their guitar in tune. This app has a tuner which can help you tune your guitar to standard EADGBe tuning. But you may be in situations where you need to tune the guitar manually without a tuner. As a beginner you may find that manual tuning is very difficult and very frustrating.</string>
    <string name="level2_lesson1_tv2"><b>Fifth fret trick</b>
                                    \n\nThe fifth fret trick is the most common method of relative tuning and is outlined below:
                                    \n\n1.	Estimate the pitch of the 6th string (the thickest string). There are lots of ways you can do this, the easiest way being just use you ear alone and guess. Alternatively, your ear can be guided by a pitch pipe, tuning fork, audio tuning guide, or the E on another instrument, such as a keyboard.
                                    \n\n2.	Place and hold a finger on the 5th fret of the 6th string then pluck the 6th string followed by the 5th string. These two notes should be the same (A). Once you\'ve tuned the open A (5th string) you can continue with the rest of the strings.
                                    \n\n3.	Play the 5th fret of the 5th string (the note should be D) and tune the 4th string to the same pitch.
                                    \n\n4.	Play the 5th fret of the 4th string (G) and tune the 3rd string accordingly.
                                    \n\n5.	Play the 4th fret of the 3rd string (B) and tune the 2nd string accordingly.
                                    \n\n6.	Play the 5th of the 2nd string (E) and tune the 1st string accordingly.
                                    \n\nTip - When using an amplifier you can make tuning easier by turning the volume up. Listen out for a wobbling sound; notice how this sound slows down as you get closer to the right tuning. This wobbling sound should stop when you are in tune and is easier to hear on the higher sounding strings.
                                    </string>

    <string name="level2_lesson2_title">Lesson 2: How to Restring a Guitar</string>
    <string name="level2_lesson2_tv1">You may need to restring your guitar from time to time. This may because a string may break or maybe the strings just need changing if they get dull and dirty. Here we look at how to change strings for both an electric and an acoustic guitar.</string>
    <string name="level2_lesson2_tv2">\n<b>Standard electric guitars</b>
                                \n\n1.	Unwind all of the machineheads and remove the old strings. This can be made easier with string winders and string cutters.
                                \n\n2.	Place the new string through the hole in the bridge. This is usually accessed on the reverse side of the body.
                                \n\n3.	Thread the string through the string-post then cut the string, leaving 5cm (approx.) of length spare.
                                \n\n4.	Wrap the string around the tuning peg then tighten the machinehead, leaving some slack on the string. Tighten until the string supports itself.
                                \n\n5.	Repeat steps 2-4 for all of the strings.
                                \n\n6.	Tune each string to the correct pitch.
                                \n\n7.	Stretch each string by pulling it away from the fretboard.
                                \n\n8.	Tune each string to the correct pitch again. If you find that the strings are slipping out of tune repeat steps 7 and 8. This should stabilise the tuning.
                                \n\n<b>Acoustic/classical guitars</b>
                                \n\n1.	Unwind one of the machineheads and remove the old string. This can be made easier with string winders and string cutters.
                                \n\n2.	Tie the new string to the bridge, making sure you mimic the method used to tie the old strings (this is why you should change just one string to start with).
                                \n\n3.	Thread the new string through the string-post then cut the string, leaving 5cm (approx.) of length spare.
                                \n\n4.	Wrap the string around the tuning peg then tighten the machinehead, leaving some slack on the string. Tighten until the string supports itself.
                                \n\n5.	Repeat steps 1-4 for all of the strings.
                                \n\n6.	Tune each string to the correct pitch.
                                \n\n7.	Stretch each string.
                                \n\n8.	To ensure stable tuning repeat steps 6 and 7.</string>

    <string name="level2_lesson3_title">Lesson 3: Getting to know the Fretboard</string>
    <string name="level2_lesson3_tv1">Frets are the silver strips of metal that run up and down the entire length of (most) guitar fretboards, or the front face of the guitar neck. If you hold down a string between different frets while plucking that same string throughout, you\'ll notice the pitch of your notes change each time you go over a new fret wire. This is because the main job of frets is to control the intonation of each string, helping guitarists select which notes and chords they play.</string>
    <string name="level2_lesson3_tv2">The inlaid dots on the fretboard are fret markers that indicate specific fret numbers. The double dot indicates that it is one octave above the open string, therefore restarting the notes in the series. Typically, these dots follow this pattern:
                                    \n\n1st single dot = 3rd fret
                                    \n2nd single dot = 5th fret
                                    \n3rd single dot = 7th fret
                                    \n4th single dot = 9th fret
                                    \nDouble dot = 12th fret
                                    \n5th single dot = 15th fret
                                    \n6th single dot = 17th fret
                                    \n7th single dot = 19th fret
                                    \n8th single dot = 21st fret
                                    </string>

    <string name="level2_lesson4_title">Lesson 4: How to Read Guitar Chord Charts</string>
    <string name="level2_lesson4_tv1">A trick to learning chord charts is to stand your guitar so that the headstock is pointing directly up. Then look at 4 frets. That\'s your basic chord chart. The 6 vertical lines represent 6 strings, although, the names of the strings rarely ever appear on the actual chord chart itself. The horizontal lines represent the metal frets, but again, these numbers usually don\'t appear on the chord chart. The black dots represent where you put your fingers. The dots are number telling you what finger you should be placing there.</string>
    <string name="level2_lesson4_tv2">It\s vital that you learn to read chord charts. And it is pretty easy once you get used to it. If you see an "0" above one of the vertical lines, it means that the open string is played. No finger should be placed on that string. If you see an "X" above one of the vertical lines, it means that particular string shouldn\'t be played at all. If you see a number next to the top horizontal line, it means that you should start forming the chord based on that numbered fret. In the example, left, you would start on the 7th fret (imagine the 7th fret as the nut of the guitar), putting a finger on the 8th fret of the 4th string and another finger on the 10th fret of the 3rd string.</string>
    <string name="level2_lesson4_tv3">It\s absolutely vital that you know how to read chord charts, it will open so many doors for you as a guitarist becuase you will be able to learn any chord you wish once you know how</string>



    <string name="level2_lesson5_title">Lesson 5: How to Read Guitar Tabs</string>
    <string name="level2_lesson5_tv1">Reading tablature (guitar tab) is quite simple, and the main advantage of learning to read tabs is that you can find tabs of almost any song or guitar solo online for free.</string>
    <string name="level2_lesson5_tv2">The way tabs are displayed is the same as if you rotated your guitar neck so that it\'s facing you. The letters all the way to the left are the names of the six strings from highest to lowest, and the dashes running horizontally are there to represent the strings themselves. The numbers represent which fret to play, the 0\'s represent that you play an open string, and the x\'s represent a string that isn\'t played. It\'s a lot like reading chord charts in that way. Most of the time you won\'t find x\'s in tabs, but they are occasionally used to represent chords. The diagram above shows how a D major chord is written in tablature.
    \n\nMost guitar tabs you\'ll come across online will look like this (see below):
    </string>


    <string name="level3_intro_title">Level 3: Introduction</string>
    <string name="level3_intro_tv1">Welcome to the third level of GuitarPal!</string>
    <string name="level3_intro_tv2">\nIn this level, you will be introduced to some basic chords. There are two main types of chords, Major and Minor. Major chords sound happy and Minor chords sound sad. Once you learn these chords, try and switch between these chords and play around with them. The chords shown in this level are in the same key of Gmajor so it will sound perfectly fine to jam around between these chords and you can even write 1000s of songs with these chords! So swipe the screen to the left and lets begin!\n\n Or alternatively you can take the level 3 test now!</string>

    <string name="level3_lesson1_title">Lesson 1: G Major Chord</string>
    <string name="level3_lesson1_tv1">Remember from the previous level that the \'o\' means this string is played open. So here\'s how to play a GMajor chord:</string>
    <string name="level3_lesson1_tv2">\n1. Place your 2nd finger on the 3rd fret of the 6th string.
                                        \n2. Place your 1st finger on the 2nd fret of the 5th string.
                                        \n3. Place your 3rd finger on the 3rd fret of the 1st string.
                                        \n4. Strum down from the 6th string. .
                                        </string>


    <string name="level3_lesson2_title">Lesson 2: D Major Chord</string>
    <string name="level3_lesson2_tv1">Remember from the previous level that the \'X\' means this string is not played. So here\'s how to play a DMajor chord:</string>
    <string name="level3_lesson2_tv2">\n1. Place your 1st finger on the 2nd fret of the 3rd string.
                                        \n2. Place your 3rd finger on the 3rd fret of the 2nd string.
                                        \n3. Place your 2nd finger on the 2nd fret of the 1st string.
                                        \n4. Strum down from the 4th string.</string>


    <string name="level3_lesson3_title">Lesson 3: C Major Chord</string>
    <string name="level3_lesson3_tv1">So here\'s how to play a CMajor chord:</string>
    <string name="level3_lesson3_tv2">\n1. Place your 1st finger on the 1st fret of the 2nd string.
                                        \n2. Place your 2nd finger on the 2nd fret of the 4th string.
                                        \n3. Place your 3rd finger on the 3rd fret of the 5th string.
                                        \n4. Strum down from the 5th string.</string>

    <string name="level3_lesson4_title">Lesson 4: E Minor Chord</string>
    <string name="level3_lesson4_tv1">So here\'s how to play a EMinor chord:</string>
    <string name="level3_lesson4_tv2">\n1. Place your 2nd finger on the 2nd fret of the 5th string.
                                        \n2. Place your 3rd finger on the 2nd fret of the 4th string.
                                        \n3. Strum down from the 6th string
                                        </string>

    <string name="level3_lesson5_title">Lesson 5: A Minor Chord</string>
    <string name="level3_lesson5_tv1">So here\'s how to play a AMinor chord:</string>
    <string name="level3_lesson5_tv2">\n1. Place your 2nd finger on the 2nd fret of the 4th string.
                                        \n2. Place your 3rd finger on the 2nd fret of the 3rd string.
                                        \n3. Place your 1st finger on the 1st fret of the 2nd string.
                                        \n4. Strum down from the 5th string.
                                        </string>

    <string name="level4_intro_title">Level 4: Introduction</string>
    <string name="level4_intro_tv1">Welcome to the 4th level of Guitar Pal! You are certainly making excellent progress!</string>
    <string name="level4_intro_tv2">\nIn this level, we are going to have a look at some more advanced aspects of learning guitar such as learning strumming patterns and in particular, scales. We we also have a look at some good practice techniques to start taking note of and start getting into the habit of practicing. So swipe left and lets begin!\n\n Or alternatively you can take the level 4 test now!</string>

    <string name="level4_lesson1_title">Lesson 1: Strumming Patterns</string>
    <string name="level4_lesson1_tv1">Strumming patterns are extremely important and are often overlooked. If you learn one particular strumming pattern, you can then apply it to so many songs or even use the pattern to write your own songs. You can then experiment with the pattern by changing the speed, volume, varying the dynamics of your playing or by adding and removing strums in certain areas, they are just great to play around with. And once you learn one, you can move onto various other patterns. In the Practical Support section of this app, there is a strumming pattern chart with 8 common patterns to get you going!
                                        \n\nHave a go at the ones below. You can keep a steady beat in your by counting 1-2-3-4 over and over in your head or out loud as you play the pattern.  If you struggle with the beats in between, you can use the word \‘and\’ to fill these gaps.
                                        \nSo you can count: 1-and-2-and-3-and-4 over and over to help keep time. Once you know the strumming pattern in your head without looking at the chart, you can play it along with the Metronome in this app
                                        </string>
    <string name="level4_lesson1_tv2">Tip: Be sure to keep your strumming forearm and wrist relaxed while strumming. Keep the motions fluid and avoid stiffness. 
                                    \n\nTip: Make sure that you are hitting both your downstrokes and upstrokes with the same amount of intensity and volume. This will definitely take some practice to get the technique just right.</string>

    <string name="level4_lesson2_title">Lesson 2: Power Chords</string>
    <string name="level4_lesson2_tv1">Power chords are quite easy to play and they sound especially great on an electric guitar with distortion chords, countless songs use them this way. They give you the heavy and powerful sound, hence the name Power Chord. Here\'s how to play the power chord shape:
                                       \n\n 1. Place your 1st finger on the 2nd fret of the 6th string.
                                        \n2. Place your 3rd finger on the 4th fret of the 5th string.
                                        \n3. Place your 4th finger on the 4th fret of the 4th string.
                                        \n4. Strum down from the 6th string, do not play bottom three strings.
                                        </string>
    <string name="level4_lesson2_tv2">You can play this shape anywhere along the low E string on the fretboard and you can move all three finger down a string and do the same along the A string to get every type of power chord!</string>

    <string name="level4_lesson3_title">Lesson 3: The Chromatic Scale</string>
    <string name="level4_lesson3_tv1">A scale is simply a set of notes arranged in order of pitch. They are named by the first note of the sequence. This is called the root note. Scales can ascend in pitch or descend in pitch. There are only 12 different notes that you can play on the guitar. They are labelled as:
                                        \n\n<b>A	A#	B	C	C#	D	D#	E	F	F#	G	G#</b>
                                        \n\nYour guitar has a chromatic layout. Each open string on a guitar is tuned to a certain note, as shown below:
                                        \n\nYour guitar has a chromatic layout. This basically means it goes up and down in semi-tones. The chromatic scale is basically made up of these semi tone notes. Each fret produces the next note in the chromatic scale. For example the notes on the E string are shown below:
                                        </string>
    <string name="level4_lesson3_tv2">And that’s all there is to the chromatic scale. Sounds simple but if you try and use all four fingers playing 4 notes on each string and then change between strings, it can be tricky but it is great to practice for the dexterity of your fingers!</string>

    <string name="level4_lesson4_title">Lesson 4: The Major Scale</string>
    <string name="level4_lesson4_tv1">Before we can explain how the major scale is formed, you must understand the intervals between the named notes. There are whole steps between A-B, C-D, D-E, F-G, G-A and half steps between B-C, E-F. You can see here below:</string>
    <string name="level4_lesson4_tv2">Each major scale is related to a major key.  For example, the key of C (major) corresponds to the C Major Scale.  When indicating a major key, you can omit the word major. When you first practice scales, I recommend playing from root not to root note ascending and descending.  The notes, in order are:
    \n\n<b>C–D–E–F–G–A-B–C–B-A-G-F–E–D–C</b>
    \n\nYou can see below this is the Cmajor scale. It starts on the 8th fret on the 6th string. Have a go playing this to the last string and then back again in the same order. You can move this scale position up and down the fret board to get other scales too! For example, more this entire scale one fret to the left and you get the BMajor scale!</string>

    <string name="level4_lesson5_title">Lesson 5: 9 Practicing Techniques</string>
    <string name="level4_lesson5_tv1">Now that you have started learning chords and scales, its time to take note of these 9 very useful practicing techniques and tips!</string>
    <string name="level4_lesson5_tv2">\n1.Have your guitar close to hand in your bedroom because it encourages practice!
                                   \n\n 2.	Have a comfortable practise environment. Keep your wrist, hand and back posture correct and you will be able to practice for longer.
                                    \n\n3.	Keeping your wrists relaxed helps stamina and speed and will help prevent cramp.
                                    \n\n4.	Keep trying to push yourself mentally and physically but do not strain your wrists too much. Repetitive strain injury is possible from playing guitar and it can interfere with practice, and it hurts.
                                    \n\n5.	Take regular breaks when you practice (around 5 minutes every half an hour). This enables you to mentally record progress and music you have made, reflecting on what you have done also gives your wrists a break.
                                    \n\n6.	Don\'t play the same material every day otherwise you will develop a "comfort zone" and you will be useless at all music outside that zone.
                                    \n\n7.	Don\'t be afraid to try out different tunings. Sometimes new creative ideas come from playing in different tunings. Also, invest in buying a capo! You won\t regret it and allows you to change key very quickly!
                                    \n\n8.	Warm-ups are essential. They help you play for longer and keep your wrists healthy. Jumping straight into fast and difficult music can be damaging to your wrist and your confidence. Don\'t forget, even professional guitarists can sound terrible without a proper warm up. Or if they haven\'t played in a while.
                                    \n\n9.	Use the metronome in this app regularly. Use it to warm-up with scales.</string>

    <string name="level5_intro_title">Level 5: Introduction</string>
    <string name="level5_intro_tv1">Welcome to the final level of GuitarPal! You have made fantastic progress to get here! Your knowledge of the guitar is clearly growing. Now let\'s keep going for the final stretch and complete the course!</string>
    <string name="level5_intro_tv2">\nIn this final level, we will look at some more advanced techniques that beginners can learn. These are very useful and are essential to any guitarist. This level includes lessons on palm muting, slide, vibrato, arpeggiated chords, hammer-ons and pull-offs. So lets begin the final level and complete the course with style! \n\n Or alternatively you can take the final level 5 test now!</string>

    <string name="level5_lesson1_title">Lesson 1: Palm Muting</string>
    <string name="level5_lesson1_tv1">Palm muting is a technique where the picking hand mutes the strings whilst they are being struck. The strings are muted just in front of the bridge with the edge of the palm. Despite the name, palm muting does not produce the same effect as fret hand muting. Fret hand muting involves dampening the strings so that a percussive click is produced instead of a pitch. With palm muting it is possible to hold down frets and produce pitches, although they are more percussive than normal.
                                        \n\n1. The area on the edge of your palm (opposite the thumb) should lie across the string(s) within two inches of the bridge. The closer you are to the bridge, the lighter the palm mute will be.
                                        \n2. You don\'t need to press down with your palm. Just the weight of your hand relaxing on the strings should apply enough pressure. Remember, if you press down too hard then you\'ll completely mute the strings, if you press down too lightly then some strings may ring out.
                                        \n3. If you want to be a good rock guitarist you must be able to apply palm muting to power chords, so don\'t just practice palm muting single notes.
                                        \n4. If you\’re using an electric guitar, to get a good sound it helps to add distortion and turn up the bass on the tone control.
                                        \n\nThere are loads of ways that you can practice your palm muting. You could learn riffs that use palm muting, play your regular warm ups and exercises palm muted or play scales palm muted. Below is a good exercise for you to try:
                                        </string>

    <string name="level5_lesson2_title">Lesson 2: Slide</string>
    <string name="level5_lesson2_tv1">Sliding is a form of legato (smooth playing) that is similar to hammer-ons and pull-offs. The technique involves playing a note and then moving the finger to a different fret (keeping the finger pressed firmly against the fretboard as you move).</string>
    <string name="level5_lesson2_tv2"><b>Instructions:</b>
                                    \n\n1. Place your 1st finger on the 5th fret of the 1st string (the highest, thinnest string)
                                    \n\n2. Pluck the string
                                    \n\n3. Whilst holding your finger firmly against the fretboard, drag your finger up to the 7th fret (passing the 6th fret along the way)
                                    \n\nThe slide should sound like a swift transition from the 5th fret through to the 7th fret. The finger should remain pressed against the fretboard at all times, otherwise the sound will be cut.
                                    </string>

    <string name="level5_lesson3_title">Lesson 3: Vibrato</string>
    <string name="level5_lesson3_tv1">Vibrato is a wavering/wobbling effect from sudden changes in pitch. This is achieved by wiggling the finger whilst a note is fretted. Vibrato can also be added with the whammy bar. The example below shows vibrato on the 12th fret of the B-string, followed by wide vibrato:</string>

    <string name="level5_lesson4_title">Lesson 4: Bends</string>
    <string name="level5_lesson4_tv1">String bending is a basic guitar technique, used a lot in blues and rock but also found a bit in most other styles (except classical). It is a technique that is mainly used on the electric guitar but can also be used on an acoustic if used well. The idea is to "bend" (push a string across or over the fingerboard with your left hand fingers) so that the string gets tighter and the pitch goes up. You can do a half bend which pushes the pitch up a semi-tone or a full bend which pushes the pitch up a tone. You can see bends here below as well as a 1 and a half bend which pushes the pitch up 3 semitones.
                                    </string>

    <string name="level5_lesson5_title">Lesson 5: Hammer-ons and Pull-offs</string>
    <string name="level5_lesson5_tv1">A hammer-on is a form of legato (smooth playing) that is achieved by using a fretting hand finger to slam down onto a fret to sound a note without the need for plucking. Below is an example:</string>
    <string name="level5_lesson5_tv2"><b>Instructions:</b>
                                    \n\n1. Place the 1st finger (index finger) of your fretting hand on 5th fret of the high E-string.
                                       \n\n2.	Pluck the high E-string.
                                        \n\n3. Whilst the note is sounding, press the tip of your second finger (middle finger) down onto the 6th fret.
                                        \n\n4. The note on fret 6 should sound as you hammer on.
                                    </string>

    <string name="level5_lesson5_tv3">\nA pull-off is the opposite of a hammer-on. Quickly taking a finger off a fret to sound a note below it (on the same string).</string>
    <string name="level5_lesson5_tv4"><b>Instructions:</b>
                                    \n\n1. With your 2nd finger hold down the 6th fret of the high E-string.
                                        \n2. Whilst holding the 6th fret, use your 1st finger to hold down the 5th fret on the same string.
                                        \n3. Pluck the high E-string.
                                        \n4. Whilst the note is sounding, remove the 2nd finger from the string really quickly. The 5th fret should now sound.
                                        \n\nMake sure the pulled note is the same volume as the picked note. Pulling tip of your finger down slightly as you pull off will produce a louder tone.
                                        \n\nRemember - hammer-ons and pull-offs can both involve open strings. Try out various slurs (hammer-ons and pull-offs) all around the fretboard. Use different fingers and try stretching between frets that are far apart.
                                    </string>

    <string name="level1_test">Level 1 Test</string>
    <string name="level2_test">Level 2 Test</string>
    <string name="level3_test">Level 3 Test</string>
    <string name="level4_test">Level 4 Test</string>
    <string name="level5_test">Level 5 Test</string>


</resources>
